

Sophia Davis

Marketer/Full Stack Web Developer



Professional Summary

Well-qualified Full Stack Developer familiar with wide range of programming utilities and languages. Knowledgeable of backend and frontend development requirements. Handles any part of process with ease. Collaborative team player with excellent technical abilities offering years of related experience.



Work History

2020-03 -Current

Graphic Designer/Marketer

Freelacer, Columbus, Ohio

- Designed website layouts, templates and unique branded looks
- Worked with clients to gather and define requirements, establish scopes and managing project milestones
- Completed in-depth product design tests with help of different software, models and design systems
- Built corporate brands by designing cohesive looks between elements such as logos and letterheads
- Created broad range of work using various design techniques
- Completed final touches for projects such as images sizes and font selection
- Created and updated trend boards, investigated changing conditions and recommended strategic adoptions to capitalize on projected changes
- Coordinated, created and scheduled content, designs and periodic updates to company website.
- Put together videos for social media, advertising and informational purposes

2018-04 -2019-03

Certified Leasing and Sales Associate

Germain Mercedes Benz Of Easton, Columbus, Ohio

- Utilized targeted email campaigns and cold calling to increase revenue.
- Attended continuing education courses and workshops to gain additional insurance industry knowledge.
- Promoted products and services using upselling and other sales strategies.
- Exceeded corporate quotas for monthly policy sales.
- Worked independently with minimal supervision.
- Contributed to event marketing, sales and brand promotion.

2018-08 -2019-02

Marketing and management assistant

Franklin University, Columbus, Ohio

 Conducted thorough research using diverse resources to assist professional staff with routine and special project tasks



Address

New Albany, Ohio, 43054

Phone

614-804-9655

E-mail

Davisk28@email.franklin.edu

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/sophiadavis525

www

https://mavvymarketing.wixsite.com/mavvy

www

https://github.com/sdavis525



Creative Thinking

Website Design

Presentation Planning

Concept Development

Content Marketing

Responsive design

Social media management

JavaScript programming



CSS proficiency



HTML expertise



Application development



React



Good

SQL integration



API design knowledge



- Successfully completed special projects to exceed goals of both marketing department and overall organization
- Managed complex and detailed projects for executives by ensuring budget adherence and timely delivery.
- Delivered top-notch administrative support to office staff, promoting excellence in office operations.
- Volunteered to help with special projects of varying degrees of complexity.

2017-03 -2018-04

Operations manager, middle school teacher

LA Fitness, Columbus, Ohio

- Managing a team of 20+ employees
- Managing quality assurance programs, supervising, hiring, and training other employees /monitoring existing processes and analyzing their effectiveness
- Built learning and citizenship skills to help with personal growth in addition to increasing academic knowledge
- Devised processes to boost long-term business success and increase profit levels
- Worked in matrix management environment with oversight of division level managers, operations, sales, finance, human resources, safety and compliance
- Utilized multimedia strategies and technology to convey information in fresh and interesting ways.

2015-09 -2017-03

School Age Lead Teacher

YWCA Safe & Sound - School, Columbus, Ohio

- Managed two assistant teachers and oversaw volunteer staff.
- Used learning stations to incorporate colors, shapes and textures to help students develop communication skills and build relationships
- Drove student learning by establishing clear classroom plans and group objectives, as well as actionable strategies to achieve each goal
- Assessed student learning progress and comprehension with routine tests and standardized examinations
- Helped students develop self-esteem and life skills by fostering healthy conflict-resolution, critical thinking and communication
- Evaluated individual student abilities and created action plans based on current level and desired growth goals to support preparedness for transition to next grade level.



Education

2020-02 -2020-01

MBA: Marketing and Communications

Franklin University - Columbus, OH

2011-08 -2016-05

Bachelor of Arts: Family and Child Development

The University of Akron - Akron, Ohio

2022-01 -2022-07

Certificate: Full Stack Web Developer

Ohio State University - Columbus, OH